你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
现在，正如你所知道的，每一枚硬币都有两面。
Now as you know there are two sides to every coin.
现在您已经在本视频中了解了如何将软件包安装到您的系统中，接下来我们将介绍
And now that you've learned how to install packages to your system in this video we're going to be covering
如何从您的系统中卸载软件包，并确保您的系统非常干净。
how you can uninstall packages from your system and make sure that your system is squeaky clean.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's just go ahead and get right into it.
好的。
OK.
在最后几个视频中，我们一直在摆弄x11应用程序包，我们将继续
So in the last few videos we've been messing around with the x 11 apps package and we're going to continue
在这段视频中把它当做我们的小白鼠。
using that as kind of our guinea pig for this video.
因此，要想卸载软件包，最基本的方法是键入sudo apt get remove和
So to uninstall a package in a boon to the most basic way to do it is to type sudo apt get remove and
然后是包名。
then the package name.
好的，因为我们谈论的是x11应用程序包，所以我们只需输入sudo、apt、get、remove，然后输入x
OK so because we are talking about the x 11 apps package we just type sudo apt get remove and then x
11个应用程序。
11 apps.
这会把它去掉，但这不是首选的方法。
And that would remove it but that's not the preferred way to do it.
好的。
OK.
原因是当您安装软件包时，有时会出现配置文件
And the reason is when you install packages there are sometimes configuration files that come along
使用软件包，如果只使用sudo apt get remove删除软件包，则配置
with the packages and if you just remove the package using sudo apt get remove then the configuration
文件被留在您的系统上，占用空间，没有任何帮助。
files are left behind on your system taking up space and not being helpful.
现在，如果您想在将来再次安装软件包并想要您的所有设置，这会很有用
Now this can be useful if you want to install the package again in the future and want all your settings
都是一样的，但这仍然不是最好的方式。
to be the same but it's still not really the preferred way to do it.
相反，要删除软件包及其所有配置文件，我们要做的不是键入siap
Instead to remove a package and all of its configuration files what we do is instead of typing silap
Get Remove，我们键入sudo apt get perge，然后输入包名。
get removed we type sudo apt get Perge and then the package name.
就像我是个伪君子。
Like I a pseudo get purred.
优秀的应用程序现在清除将删除软件包及其配置文件。
Excellent apps now the purge will remove the package and its configuration files.
因此，无论您想要安装什么软件包，都要始终使用Perge。
So always use Perge whatever you want to install a package.
所以如果我继续这样做，它就会说，嘿，我想去掉这个，没问题。
So if I go ahead and do that it's going to go and say hey I want to remove this is OK.
我按“是”。
I press yes.
我将检查并删除x11应用程序和它的任何配置文件，这样您就可以在这里看到它写着
I will go through and remove x 11 apps and any of its configuration files so you can see here it says
正在清除x 11个应用的配置文件。
purging configuration files for x 11 apps.
好的，所以它继续前进，并做到了这一点。
OK so it's gone ahead and done that.
现在，这11个应用程序包将从系统中100%删除。
Now that will have the 11 apps package 100 percent removed from the system.
但有时当您安装软件包时，您需要安装其他10个不同的软件包作为依赖项。
But sometimes when you install packages you need to install like 10 other different packages as dependencies.
好的，为了让您想要安装的软件包正常工作，您需要像其他10个软件包一样
OK so you need in order to get the package that you want to install to work you need like 10 other packages
或者甚至是上百个套餐，才能让这个套餐发挥作用。
or maybe even a hundred of the packages in order to get that one package to work.
我们称这些额外的套餐为依赖关系。
And we call those extra packages dependancies.
因此，如果不再需要这些依赖项，但您不知道它们叫什么，如何删除
So if those dependencies are no longer required but you don't know what they're called How can you remove
他们。
them.
您很幸运，可以删除作为依赖项安装但不再是依赖项的软件包
Well you're in luck in order to remove packages that were installed as dependencies but are no longer
系统上的任何其他软件包都需要。
required for any other package on the system.
你可以只做sudo Factory，屏幕sudo apt自动删除，仅此而已。
You can just do sudo factory the screen sudo apt get auto remove and that's it.
因此，sudo get或立即删除或要删除将自动删除任何悬空依赖项，这些依赖项
So sudo get or to remove now or to remove will automatically remove any dangling dependencies that are
不再需要，这可以帮助您节省系统空间。如果我这样做了，它会告诉我有
no longer required which helps you save space on your systems if I do that it's going to tell me there's
实际上没有任何需要移除的，但是这样可以节省很多空间。
actually not any that need to be removed but you can save a lot of space in this.
因此请记住，这一切都发生在您的产品上数百个甚至数千个不同的包中
So bear in mind this is all happening across hundreds or even thousands of different packages on your
系统，并让包管理器自动保持一切有序，这真的是一项很大的资产。
system and having the package manager keep everything in order automatically is a really great asset.
我相信你也会同意这总比你自己做好。
I'm sure you'd agree it beats doing it yourself anyway.
现在，每当您下载并安装软件包或软件包的副本时，都会将其本地保存在您的计算机上。
Now whenever you download and install a package or a copy of the package is saved locally on your computer.
现在，如果该软件包随后被解包并存储在您的系统上，那么当您安装时，它就是这样工作的
Now if this package is then unpacked and stored on your systems that's how it works when you install
软件包以压缩存档的形式下载自身，然后将其解压缩并安装在您的系统上。
a package download itself as a compressed archive then unpacks itself and installs itself on your system.
好的。
OK.
因为两步过程不仅在您系统上安装了软件包，而且还安装了压缩版本
Because that two step process not only has a package installed on your system but a compressed version
至少压缩文件通常会占用空间，如果您
of it is also saved at least compressed files usually take up space and aren't really necessary if you
已经安装了软件包，因为它们只是您知道的像包装器这样的归档文件
already have the package installed and because they're just you know an archive like the wrapper that
和这些东西一起来的。
comes with the stuff.
好的。
OK.
因此，您实际上可以在千兆字节的空间之间为自己节省大量空间，只需删除
So you can actually save yourself massive amounts of space between gigabytes of space just by deleting
这些档案。
these archives.
好的。
OK.
现在这些档案都被储存起来了。
Now these archives are stored.
如果我们访问劈开变量劈开缓存劈开应用劈开存档。
If we go that slash var slash cache slash apt slash archive.
所以如果我们去那里看一看，我们可以说这里有相当多的死角，一些压缩的
So if we go there and take a look we can say there's quite a few little deadfalls here some compressed
存档已保存，然后您可以看到用于x11应用程序的存档，尽管我们实际上已将其从
archives saved and then you can see the one for x 11 apps even though we've actually removed it from
这个系统。
the system.
您可以通过使用El-hage命令执行ls来查看它们有多大。
And you can see how large these are by doing ls with the El-Hage command.
你可以看到里面总共有大约10兆字节，这并不多。
And you can see that there's a total of about 10 megabytes in there and that's not much.
但是您知道，在您的系统上不断安装软件包之后，这个容量很容易增长到千兆字节。
But you know this can easily grow to gigabytes after you keep installing packages on your system.
它可能会变得非常疯狂，因为您安装的每个包都有自己的依赖项。
It can get quite mad because every package you install comes with its own dependencies.
即使是这些依赖项也会保存为副本，因此您可以通过删除
And even those dependencies are saved as copies so you can really save a lot of space by removing the
这里的东西。
stuff from here.
现在您甚至不需要在文件夹中就可以删除它们，所以如果我只需返回到我们的主目录
Now you don't have to even be in the folder to remove them so if I just head back to our home directory
在那里您可以看到，如果我们运行sudo apt get lean，我们的主目录在哪里，这将删除所有
and there you can see where our home directory if we run sudo apt get clean that will delete all of
该目录中的软件包。
the packages from that directory.
如果我们备份到劈开变量劈开缓存劈开和劈开归档到一个地址，我们可以看到
If we had back up into the slash var slash cache slash and slash archives into an address we can see
那也不是。
that either.
或者被删除了，尽管我们不在那个文件夹里。
Or been deleted even though we weren't in that folder.
所以，如果你想把那些东西都扔掉，那就最好把它清理干净。
So if you want to get rid of all that stuff do sudo apt get clean.
但有时，不管出于什么原因，你都不想把它们全部删除，你只想把它们去掉
But sometimes you don't want to delete all of those for whatever reason and you only want to get rid
你想扔掉的东西，那些包裹，那些存档，但是那些包裹
of the stuff you want to get rid of those packages those those those archives but the ones for packages
不能再从实际的阿蓬特排斥区域访问，这通常是
that can no longer be accessed from the from the actual Aponte repulsive areas that this is usually
适用于那些非常陈旧的系统，并且想要让他们的现金持续运行数年，然后
for systems that are very old and want to keep their cash going for years and years and years and then
从现在开始，只需修剪树叶，去掉不能再下载的deb包
from now and then just trim the leaves and get rid of the deb packages that can no longer be downloaded
不管出于什么原因，要做到这一点，而不是使用sudo apt清理。
for whatever reason and to do that instead of using sudo apt get clean.
您现在确实使用了自动清除，因为这只是为了突出显示清除会清除归档中的所有内容
You do use auto clean now as just to highlight clean gets rid of everything of those in the archive
不同于列表缓存的缓存。
cache that is different from the from the list cache.
顺便说一句，这只是一个存储空间，用于存放已保存的档案和包等
By the way that's just a this is just a storage space for for saved archives and packages and stuff
所以这是一个完全不同的缓存。
so this is a completely different cache.
但CLEAN将删除其中的所有内容，自动清除将检查其中的内容并仅将其删除
But clean will remove everything in there and auto clean will check what's in there and only delete
您不能再从存储库下载以确保其中没有内容的文件
the ones that you can no longer download from the repositories to make sure you don't have stuff in
在那里你再也用不到了。
there that you'll never use again.
因此，他们有一个不废话的卸载包指南。
So they have a no nonsense guide to uninstalling packages.
那么我们来复习一下。
So let's review.
好的，我们讨论最基本的检查软件包的方法是使用sudo apt get remove，然后使用软件包
OK we discuss at the most basic way to review packages is to use sudo apt get remove and then the package
名字。
name.
但不建议这样做，因为它会留下配置文件。
But this is not recommended because it leaves behind configuration files.
相反，使用sudo、apt、get、perge，然后使用包名。
Instead use sudo apt get Perge and then the package name.
好的，现在当您安装软件包时，其他依赖项软件包很可能也安装在
OK now when you install the package it's likely the other dependency packages were also installed in
以使该软件包正常工作，以便消除这些依赖项并自动删除它们
order to make that package work in order to get rid of those dependencies and automatically remove them
从系统中删除。
from the system.
只要不再需要它们，您就可以使用sudo、apt、get、auto remove或删除任何不需要的
As long as they're are no longer required you would use sudo apt get auto remove or to remove any unwanted
以及所需的依赖关系。
and needed dependencies.
好的。
OK.
仅仅因为它们被用于一个包裹，而你丢掉了那个包裹，并不意味着它们不再是
And just because they were used for one package and you loof that package doesn't mean they're no longer
需要另一个。
needed for another.
不过，别担心这一点。
But don't worry about that.
包裹会为您解决所有这些问题的，好的。
The package is going to take care of all that for you OK.
您还了解到，安装软件包时，首先会将其下载并保存在您的
And you also learned that when a software package is installed it is first downloaded and saved on your
压缩存档中的系统。
system in a compressed archive.
即使安装了软件包，此归档在您的系统上也是安全的。
This archive is safe on your system even if the package is installed.
这意味着它正在占据空间。
And that means it's taking up space.
它不像你真正想要的东西背后的包装或包装。
It's not like the wrapper or the packaging behind the actual thing that you want.
好的，所以要清理所有的包装，清理所有的东西，无论做什么都是为了清理干净
OK so to clean up all the packaging and clean up all that stuff what ever do is sudo apt get clean and
这将删除所有压缩包存档，并为您节省大量空间。
that's going to delete all the compressed package archives and save you a heck of a lot of space.
您有时甚至会惊讶于千兆字节。
You'll be surprised sometimes even gigabytes at times.
但也许您出于某种原因不想清理所有这些包，而是说您只需
But perhaps you don't want to clean up all of those packages for some reason and instead said you just
我想清理那些不能再从Buntu存储库下载的文件。
want to clean up the ones that can no longer be downloaded from the buntu repositories.
因此，您可以使用sudo进行自动清洗。
So for that you use sudo to get auto clean.
好的，现在你就知道了。
OK so there you have it.
你认识的漂亮的人。
Beautiful people you know.
您需要了解的有关包管理的所有内容InnoCentive，他们已经做到了
Everything that you will ever need to know about package management InnoCentive and they've done so
令人难以置信的是，在接下来的视频中，我想祝贺你们，并回顾一下我们所做的
unbelievably well that in the next video I would like to congratulate you and have a recap of what we've
学到了东西。
learned.
因此，为了得到一些当之无愧的赞扬和回顾，我将在下一个视频中与你见面。
So for some well-deserved praise and a recap I'll see you in the next video.